export const gst113Questions = [
  {
    question: "The name Nigeria was suggested by____",
    options: ["Flora Shaw", "Lord Lugard", "Taubman Goldie", "Consul Phillip"],
    answer: "Flora Shaw",
  },
  {
    question: "____ instituted the elective principles.",
    options: [
      "Clifford Constitution",
      "Richards Constitution",
      "Independence Constitution",
      "Oliver Littleton Constitution",
    ],
    answer: "Clifford Constitution",
  },
  {
    question: "The first Prime Minister of Nigeria was___",
    options: [
      "Dr. Michael Okpara",
      "Chief Obafemi Awolowo",
      "Sir Tafawa Balewa",
      "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
    ],
    answer: "Sir Tafawa Balewa",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The institutionalization of the structural adjustment programme in Nigeria was during the era of ___",
    options: [
      "General Yakubu Gowon",
      "General Sanni Abacha",
      "General Ibrahim Babangida",
      "General Muhammadu Buhari",
    ],
    answer: "General Ibrahim Babangida",
  },
  {
    question: "Nigeria became a Republic in___",
    options: ["1963", "1964", "1962", "1966"],
    answer: "1963",
  },
  {
    question: "The move to Abuja was initiated by__",
    options: [
      "General Murtala Mohammed",
      "Alhaji Shehu Shagari",
      "General Sanni Abacha",
      "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
    ],
    answer: "General Murtala Mohammed",
  },
  {
    question: "By 1963, the population of Nigeria grew to___",
    options: ["55.7million", "52million", "88.9million", "165million"],
    answer: "55.7million",
  },
  {
    question: "Monarchical ascendancy in the Igbo subsection was by_____",
    options: [
      "achievement",
      "seniority",
      "patriarchy primogeniture",
      "chieftaincy",
    ],
    answer: "achievement",
  },
  {
    question: "The jihad of Uthman Dan Fodio started in___",
    options: ["1808", "1810", "1804", "1830"],
    answer: "1804",
  },
  {
    question: "The first missionary sent by the CMS to Nigeria was___",
    options: [
      "Henry Townsend",
      "Reverend Father Lutz",
      "Father Conquard",
      "Bishop Ajayi Crowther",
    ],
    answer: "Henry Townsend",
  },
  {
    question: "The first military coup in Nigeria took place on the___",
    options: [
      "15th April, 1966",
      "16th January, 1966",
      "15th January, 1966",
      "17th January, 1966",
    ],
    answer: "15th January, 1966",
  },
  {
    question: "Two Nigeria major tribes are___",
    options: [
      "Hausa and Edo",
      "Ibibio and Niger Delta",
      "Yoruba and Ibo",
      "Fulani and Ijaws",
    ],
    answer: "Yoruba and Ibo",
  },
  {
    question: "The first newspaper in Nigeria was called___",
    options: ["National Daily", "Vanguard", "Nigerian Observer", "Iwe-Irohin"],
    answer: "Iwe-Irohin",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ defined culture as that complex whole which includes knowledge belief, art, law, morals, customs and other capabilities and habits acquired by man as a member of the society",
    options: [
      "Edward B. Tylor",
      "Horton and Hunt",
      "Spencer-Oatay",
      "Smith D.E.",
    ],
    answer: "Edward B. Tylor",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The process by which people learn the characteristics of their group like behaviour, knowledge, attitude, values, norms and other orientation that suit the group is called__",
    options: ["socialization", "social context", "acquisitive", "mutable"],
    answer: "socialization",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The culture that is inter-woven and inter-connected is called___",
    options: ["incorporating", "continuous", "receptive", "universal"],
    answer: "incorporating",
  },
  {
    question: "The central homeland of the Hausa covers an area about___",
    options: [
      "640 kilometers wide",
      "740 kilometers",
      "840 kilometers wide",
      "940 kilometers wide",
    ],
    answer: "640 kilometers wide",
  },
  {
    question: "Bayajidda is associated with the origin of___",
    options: ["Hausa states", "Benin Kingdom", "Kanuri Empire", "Oyo Empire"],
    answer: "Hausa states",
  },
  {
    question: "Before 1804, Hausaland was ruled by___",
    options: [
      "Habe Kings",
      "fuling ruling class",
      "appointire ruling class",
      "nomadic Fulanis",
    ],
    answer: "Habe Kings",
  },
  {
    question: "The original Fulani language is___",
    options: ["fulfulde", "Yan Bori", "Sarkin Rafi", "Kabewa"],
    answer: "fulfulde",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the highly cherished and celebrated festivals among the Fulani___",
    options: ["Gelede", "Awon Iya Wa", "Ugie Erha Oba", "Sharo"],
    answer: "Sharo",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the ninth century A.D, black-smithing and agriculture had emerged at___",
    options: ["Oyo", "Ondo", "Ilorin", "Ife"],
    answer: "Ife",
  },
  {
    question: "Urbanism was a way of life of__",
    options: ["Hausa", "Yoruba", "Binni", "Isoko"],
    answer: "Yoruba",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The two new states that emerged after the fall of Oyo Empire founded by war time refugees were___",
    options: [
      "Egbado and Ifonyin",
      "Ijebu and Ijesha",
      "Ketu and Owo",
      "Ibadan and Egba",
    ],
    answer: "Ibadan and Egba",
  },
  {
    question: "Ogiso rulers existed in___",
    options: [
      "Benin Kingdom",
      "Oyo Empire",
      "Hausa States",
      "Kanem-Bornu Empire",
    ],
    answer: "Benin Kingdom",
  },
  {
    question: "Olokun in Benin is the god of___",
    options: [
      "Iron",
      "god of death",
      "the goddess of safe delivery",
      "global waters",
    ],
    answer: "global waters",
  },
  {
    question: "The city of Nri is reflected to be the origin of___",
    options: [
      "Yoruba culture",
      "Bini culture",
      "Fulani culture",
      "Igbo culture",
    ],
    answer: "Igbo culture",
  },
  {
    question: "Core beliefs mean___",
    options: [
      "ascribed to someone who has not thought about the issue",
      "beliefs that are actively thought about",
      "dispositional beliefs",
      "belief formation",
    ],
    answer: "beliefs that are actively thought about",
  },
];
